Philip Singer Papers
Philip Singer Papers
- Research files
  - Spontaneous Healing
    - Spontaneous Healing, Andrew Weil M.D., singer_p_0200; description on tape reads, "How to discover and enhance your body's natural ability to maintain and heal itself"; VHS; running time 76:00 (Box 40)
    - Spontaneous Healing, Andrew Weil M.D.; Eight Weeks to Optimum Health, Andrew Weil, M.D., singer_p_0201; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 40)
  - "Sri Ramana: The Sage of Arunagiri" Aksharajna, 1942 (Box 18)
  - Subincision
    - The Arunta: A Study of a Stone Age People, 1927 (Box 18)
    - Coming into being among the Australian aborigines, 1937 (Box 18)
    - Comments on the Australian subincision ceremony, 1966-1968 (Box 18)
    - Kangaroo, 1968 (Box 18)
    - "Masculinity and Mutilation in a Primitive Society," Richard A. Gould, 1968 (Box 18)
    - The meaning of subincision of the urethra to aboriginal Australians, 1966 (Box 18)
    - The native tribes of central Australia, 1899 (Box 18)
    - The origin of subincision in Australia, 1937 (Box 18)
    - Stress, 1962-1964 (Box 18)
    - Survey, 1965 (Box 18)
    - Traite de Zoologie, 1955 (Box 18)
    - Recordings
      - Australia Sub-incision Ritual: Arunta Aboringine, singer_p_1062; DVD; running time 12:00 (Oversize 5)
      - Australia Sub-incision Ritual: Arunta Aboringine, singer_p_1063; DVD; running time 12:00 (Oversize 5)
      - Australia Sub-incision Ritual: Arunta Aboringine, singer_p_1064; DVD; running time 12:00 (Oversize 5)
      - Sub-incision, singer_p_1113; DVD; running time 12:00 (Oversize 5)
  - SUFI
    - SUFI Healing Order, singer_p_0512; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
    - SUFI Healing Order, Panel, singer_p_0535; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
    - SUFI Healing Order, Robert Becker, Electricity, singer_p_0526; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Suicide
    - Suicide and Marvin, MS, 1995/10/14; singer_p_1258; text on disc reads, "Marvin discusses issue of assisted suicide"; DVD; running time 13:00 (Oversize 6)
    - Suicide and Marvin, MS, 1995/10/14; singer_p_1259; text on disc reads, text on disc reads, "Bees stings in Nx home, paralyzed attitude improved, assisted suicide, drinks coffee with help"; DVD; running time 13:00 (Oversize 6)
  - Supernatural, "The Anthropologist's Encounter with the Supernatural," I.M. Lewis, 1974 (Box 18)
  - Swami, a Hindu male religious teacher
    - Religion and Behavior, Swami, 1971; singer_p_0562; Audio cassette; running time 120:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Religious Music of India, Swami Bharati, singer_p_0561; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Swami, 1970; singer_p_0670; there is illegible handwritten text on the tape; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 2)
    - Swami Nikhilananda (Tape 2 of 2), singer_p_0510; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Swami Nikhilananda, The Great Story of Awareness (Tape 1 of 2), singer_p_0524; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Swami, P. Singer as; Shahneevahar discussion, Rock in Music ED, 1971; singer_p_0699; label on tape also reads, "Conclusion - July 6-8th session), Harry Hahn and Record"; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
    - Swami: Anthropology and Philosophy/Religion, singer_p_0659; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 2)
  - Teotihuacan
    - Teotihuacan, singer_p_0432; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
    - Teotihuacan 2, singer_p_0433; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
    - Teotihuacan Interviews, singer_p_0424; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
    - Teotihuacan interviews, singer_p_0434; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
    - Teotihuacan: Globalization vs Cultura Mexicana, singer_p_1195; DVD; running time 17:00 (Box 52)
      Description of film on back of case reads: "Teothihacan: Globalizacio n vs cultura mexicana es un reportaje que informa "la verdad" La verdad acerca de la contruccion del Walmart en San Juan, Teotihuacan. Si existe un problema, pero no es el que ha maejado en los medios de comunicacion. No existe un problema arqueologico. El walmart no interfiere en la zona arqueolgoica de Teotihuacan, ya que desde el punto mas alto del templo del sol es imposible ver el Walmart. El problema existe entre los pequenos comercios de San Juan, Teotihuacan y esta immensa cadena comercial, de los Estados Unidos, Walmart.
  - Terkel, Studs
    - Healers, Studs Terkel Re: David Hilfiger, MD, singer_p_0578; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Studs Terkel: Voices of Our Time, The Original Live Interviews (Disc 1), singer_p_1451; CD; running time 30:00 (Box 55)
      A description written on the case reads: "For five decades, Louis "Studs" Terkel, bestselling author of Working, The Good War, Coming of Age, Will the Circle Be Unbroken, and eight other books, brought artists, philosophers, scientists, and activists - the voices of our time - into our living rooms through his nationally syndicated, Peabody Award-winning radio program on WFMT in Chicago...Voices of Our Time comprises highlights from 48 of Studs' most important interviews from the 1950s to the 1990s including: Mel Brooks, Woody Allen, Daniel Ellsberg, Mahalia Jackson, Arthur Miller, Bob Woodward, Oliver Sacks, Dorothy Parker, and Ralph Ellison."
    - Studs Terkel: Voices of Our Time, The Original Live Interviews (Disc 2), singer_p_1452; CD; running time 60:00 (Box 55)
    - Studs Terkel: Voices of Our Time, The Original Live Interviews (Disc 3), singer_p_1453; CD; running time 60:00 (Box 55)
    - Studs Terkel: Voices of Our Time, The Original Live Interviews (Disc 4), singer_p_1454; CD; running time 60:00 (Box 55)
    - Studs Terkel: Voices of Our Time, The Original Live Interviews (Disc 5), singer_p_1455; CD; running time 60:00 (Box 55)
    - Studs Terkel: Voices of Our Time, The Original Live Interviews (Disc 6), singer_p_1456; CD; running time 60:00 (Box 55)
    - [Studs] Terkel and Ron David Laing, singer_p_0567; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Therapeutic touch, Dolores Krieger, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Torrepaduli
    - Pizzica -- Pizzica Torrepaduli (Unedited), singer_p_0888; label on DVD also reads, "Location, interviews (#1), dance, interview - Danielle, hippies"; DVD; running time 100:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Pizzica -- Pizzica Torrepaduli (Unedited), singer_p_0889; label on DVD also reads, "Drumming, priest location"; DVD; running time 88:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Pizzica -- Pizzica Torrepaduli (Unedited), singer_p_0890; label on DVD also reads, "Drumming (#3), priest location (#4)"; DVD; running time 88:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Pizzica -- Pizzica Torrepaduli (Unedited), singer_p_0891; label on DVD also reads, "Drumming (#3), priest location (#4)"; DVD; running time 88:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Pizzica -- Pizzica Torrepaduli (Unedited), singer_p_0892; label on DVD also reads, "Drumming (#3), priest location (#4)"; DVD; running time 88:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Pizzica -- Pizzica Torrepaduli (Unedited), singer_p_0893; label on DVD also reads, "Location, interviews (#1), dance, interview - Danielle (#2), hippies"; DVD; running time 100:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Pizzica -- Pizzica Torrepaduli (Unedited), singer_p_0906; label on DVD also reads, "Location, interviews (#1), dance, interview - Danielle, hippies"; DVD; running time 100:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Pizzica -- Pizzica Torrepaduli (Unedited), singer_p_0907; label on DVD also reads, "Location, interviews (#1), dance, interview - Danielle (#2), hippies"; DVD; running time 100:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Pizzica -- Pizzica Torrepaduli (Unedited), singer_p_0908; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Pizzica -- Pizzica Torrepaduli (Unedited), singer_p_0909; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 4)
    - Torrepaduli, singer_p_1182; label on DVD also reads, "Location, interviews, dance"; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 5)
    - Torrepaduli / Pizzica / Pizzica (Unedited), singer_p_1262; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 6)
    - Torrepaduli #1, 08/15/2006; singer_p_0369; raw footage; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 45)
      Description on tape reads, "First night - dance/drumming; Location; Interviews with students - Ita[lian] and Fr[ench]; First 20 min - montorroy."
    - Torrepaduli #2, 08/16/2006; singer_p_0370; raw footage; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 45)
      Description on tape reads, "Location, church, dance, men dance, boy dance, church worship, hippies, interview with Danielle."
    - Torrepaduli #2, singer_p_1183; label on DVD also reads, "Location, interviews Danielle, hippies, dance"; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 5)
    - Torrepaduli #3, 08/16/2006; singer_p_0371; raw footage; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 45)
      Description on tape reads, "Dance, youth, packing up, drumming."
    - Torrepaduli #3, singer_p_1184; label on DVD also reads, "drumming"; DVD; running time 60:00 (Oversize 5)
    - Torrepaduli #4, 08/18/2006; singer_p_0372; raw footage; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 45)
      Description on tape reads, "Church, Interview with the priest."
    - Torrepaduli #4, singer_p_1209; label on DVD also reads, "priest interview, location"; DVD; running time 25:00 (Oversize 6)
  - TR
    - TR #1 DIA, 12/25/1998; singer_p_0416; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
    - TR #2 DIA, 12/26/1998; singer_p_0417; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
    - TR #3 DIA, 12/06/1998; singer_p_0418; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
    - TR #4, 06/19/1996; singer_p_0419; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
    - TR #5, singer_p_0420; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
    - TR Andrea, 03/20/1997; singer_p_0422; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
    - TR Rosa, 03/14/1997; singer_p_0421; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
  - Traditional Concepts of Health and Illness in the Philippines, Michael L. Tan, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Traditional healing
    - Therapeutic opportunities, problems, and pitfalls of traditional healers in developing countries, undated (Box 24)
    - Recordings
      - Aspects of Traditional Healing and the Relationship Between Kali Mai Puja and Mental Health, BG Radio, singer_p_0539; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
      - KOK: WWJ Radio Interview, Traditional Healing and Godianism, 1978; singer_p_0773; Audio cassette; running time 15:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Traditional Healers, singer_p_0565; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
      - Traditional Healing and Kali Mai, Mental Health, singer_p_1404; CD; running time 27:00 (Box 55)
      - Traditional Healing at the Center for Forensic Psychiatry, 1978/05/31; singer_p_0532; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
      - Traditional Healing Community, singer_p_0788; text on tape reads, "A4A-DTR: 74"; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Traditional Healing, Jaime Naidu, 1977; singer_p_0515; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
      - Traditional Healing, Trado Research Center, 1977/08/15; singer_p_0753; label reads, "Trado-Center explained, metaphysics - paralysis, bone mender case, herbal garden, welcome to KOK music"; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Traditional medicine
    - Journals and reports, 1977-1987 (Box 18)
    - Lambo, TA, AIDS natural remedies, 1981-1992 (Box 24)
    - "Traditional Medicine is not Primary Health Care: A Polemic," Boris Velimirovic, Jun 1983 (Box 24)
    - World Health Organization, 1975 (Box 24)
  - Transcendental meditation, 1970; 1975-1984 (Box 18)
  - Tunisia, an account of the Tunisian question and its most recent developments, 1952 (Box 18)
  - "Tuscarora Indians, The Modal Personality Structure of the Tuscarora Indians as Revealed by the Rorschach Test," Anthony F. C. Wallace, 1952 (Box 18)
  - Unconventional medicine, "Unconventional medicine in the United States," The New England Journal of Medicine, 1993 (Box 18)
  - United States Postal Service, 1986; regarding Leroy Jenkins (Box 18)
  - USSR, Problems of Philosophy, 1966 (Box 19)
  - Vocabulary terms, fringe medicine, quackery, cults, oxford companion to medicine, 1956 (Box 19)
  - Voodoo
    - Death, 1974 (Box 24)
    - "The Ethnobiology of the Haitian Zombi," E. Wade Davis, 1983 (Box 19)
    - The "hexed" patient, 1980-1994 (Box 19)
  - Ways of Mankind
    - Ways of Mankind, Program 1 and 2, 1976; singer_p_0573; label on tape reads, "#1 language, #2 culture"; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Ways of Mankind, Program 3 and 4, singer_p_0574; label on tape reads, "#3 technology, #4 education"; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Ways of Mankind, Program 5 and 6, singer_p_0575; label on tape reads, "#5 family, #6 status and role"; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Ways of Mankind, Program 7 and 8, singer_p_0576; label on tape reads, "#7 values, #8 ethics"; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Ways of Mankind, Program 9 and 10, singer_p_0577; label on tape reads, "#9 authority, #10 summary"; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Wealth inequality, 2015 (Box 19)
  - The Whole Life Experience, 1995 (Box 19)
  - Windwalker, Wanita
    - American Indian Shaman, Mystic, Psychic Healer for our Times, An Oral Autobiography as recorded by Philip Singer, 1987 (Box 19)
    - Coreil, Jeanine, 1986 (Box 19)
    - Flyers and ads, 1987 (Box 19)
    - Medicinal therapies, undated (Box 19)
    - Medicine woman, 1986-1987 (Box 19)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 19)
    - Psychic fair, 1987 (Box 19)
    - Shaminism log, undated (Box 19)
    - Recordings
      - Healer Wanita Talks About Her Own Ovarian Cancer As Witchcraft: Santera Karla Does "Work", 1998/04/04; singer_p_1053; with Wanita Windwalker; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 5)
      - Healer Wanita Talks About Her Own Ovarian Cancer As Witchcraft: Santera Karla Does "Work", 1998/04/04; singer_p_1054; with Wanita Windwalker; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 5)
      - Healer Wanita Talks About Her Own Ovarian Cancer As Witchcraft: Santera Karla Does "Work", 1998/04/04; singer_p_1055; with Wanita Windwalker; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 5)
        A handwritten itemized list of DVD contents is included on case. It reads, "Wanita - talks about her ovarian experience - interview talks about her experience with M.D., told she has tumor, refused sur[gery]. Appealed to her Indian guides, went to alt. chiropractor - said she has worm (worm is an "energy" foster) - herbs recommended. Went to "shaman", attacked by "black mama," New Orleans, Chinese doctor in Canada. Karla works and her cards, etc "jealousy."
      - Jud CTR News Story, singer_p_1560; Mini-cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 43)
      - Judson CTR Channel 2 Films Wanita [Windwalker], singer_p_0475; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 48)
      - Justin CTR, 08/06/1989; singer_p_0476; label on case reads, "Sunday, parents, kids, staff"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 48)
      - Life and Death of an Alternative Healer, Wanita Windwalker, Shaman, Psychic, Part 1 of 2, singer_p_1212; DVD; running time 120:00 (Oversize 6)
      - Life and Death of an Alternative Healer: Wanita Windwalker, Shaman, Psychic (1929-1999) Part I of II, singer_p_0057; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 29)
      - Life and Death of an Alternative Healer: Wanita Windwalker, Shaman, Psychic (1929-1999), Part II of II, singer_p_0058; VHS; running time 30:00 (Box 29)
      - Life and Death of Wanita Windwalker (Part 1 and 2), singer_p_1380; missing 10 minutes; DVD; running time 46:00 (Box 54)
      - Wanita, singer_p_1561; Mini-cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 43)
      - Wanita, "As It Is," Diana, 1987/09/20; singer_p_0695; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Wanita, 4 Fair / Tillich-Woom, Compare Tillich and Wanita, 1987; singer_p_0694; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Wanita Tarot Dryden, 1988/10/26; singer_p_1518; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 58)
      - Wanita [Windwalker] / Reverend Campbell, Godspeed Church Choir, singer_p_0720; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Wanita [Windwalker], Goodwill Gospel Temple, 1986/07/20; singer_p_0719; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 3)
      - Wanita and M.J. Pak, 4/19/1998; singer_p_0316; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 45)
      - Wanita Hindu, singer_p_1551; Mini-cassette; running time 90:00 (Box 43)
      - Wanita Windwalker lecture in Toronto, 1985; singer_p_0631; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 2)
      - Wanita Windwalker, Choices Unlimited, 1987/06/20; singer_p_0533; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
      - Wanita/Carla, Apr 12, 1998; singer_p_0415; MiniDV; running time 60:00 (Box 46)
  - Witchcraft
    - "A Convergence of Psychological and Sociological Explainations of Witchcraft," Current Anthropology, Dec 1973 (Box 19)
    - Notes, undated (Box 19)
    - "Professor interprets witchcraft essense", 1974 (Box 19)
    - Recordings
      - Physicians and Witch Doctors: Barry Farber Interviews Dr. Philip Singer, 1978/04/15; singer_p_1074; DVD; running time 30:00 (Oversize 5)
      - Physicians and Witch Doctors: Barry Farber Interviews Dr. Philip Singer, 1978/04/15; singer_p_1075; DVD; running time 30:00 (Oversize 5)
      - Wicca, Linda Rost, First Wiccan Church, 1975/02/17; singer_p_0616; label on tape reads, "Interview with witch"; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 2)
      - Witchcraft, Lou Gordon, singer_p_0492; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 1)
      - Witchcraft and Psych (Tape 1 of 2), singer_p_0500; label on tape reads, "Singer - '75, Medical College of Ga."; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 1)
      - Witchcraft and Psychiatry, Medical College, Georgia, Philip Singer (1 of 2), singer_p_1093; DVD (Oversize 5)
      - Witchcraft and Psychology (tape 2 of 2), singer_p_0580; Audio cassette; running time 30:00 (Oversize 1)
      - Witchcraft lecture, Georgia Medical School, singer_p_0637; Singer lecture; Audio cassette; running time 90:00 (Oversize 2)
      - Witchcraft: Night Call WRIF, 1974/09/27; singer_p_0700; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 3)
  - Witch doctors, "What Western Psychotherapists Can Learn from Witch Doctors," E. Fuller Torrey, 1972 (Box 19)
  - World Health Organization
    - Dr. Kanti Girl, Nepal, WHO, Dr. Srivastiav Ind. Govt. Director Medical Services, 12/30/1975; singer_p_0525; Audio cassette; running time 60:00 (Oversize 1)
    - Health for All Kenya: WHO, singer_p_0138; VHS (Box 36)
    - WHO Mozambique, Medicine of Liberation, singer_p_1361; DVD; running time 29:00 (Box 53)
    - WHO: Bernard This Village, singer_p_1240; DVD; running time 39:00 (Oversize 6)
    - WHO: Ghana (Sankofa), singer_p_1242; primary health care through community involvement, traditional healers; DVD; running time 51:00 (Oversize 6)
    - WHO: Primary Health Care in Vietnam, singer_p_1239; DVD; running time 43:00 (Oversize 6)
    - WHO: Story of Kauko, Primary Health Care in Finland, singer_p_1241; heart disease program; DVD; running time 25:00 (Oversize 6)
  - Wounded Knee
    - Wounded Knee, 02/29/1993; singer_p_0461; text on cassette reads, "Interview with maintenance man, interview with artist Benson, interview with Lakota Language/culture, interview with Olivia, black elk heritage house"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 47)
    - Wounded Knee, 03/27/1993; singer_p_0462; text on cassette reads, "Interview with Indian boy at sign, boxing interview with Bob Starr, patient assistant, location shots, Pine Ridge, interview with 'Lloyd' at Wounded Knee sign"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 47)
    - Wounded Knee, 03/28/1993; singer_p_0463; text on cassette reads: "Interview with Bob, interview with radio station, Kili"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 47)
    - Wounded Knee, 03/30/1993; singer_p_0464; text on cassette reads, "Follow up with Olivia, Bob 'Truanly,' Phoenix, alcohol project, buffalo, interview with parks agent re: buffalo spirituality"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 47)
    - Wounded Knee, 04/04/1993; singer_p_0465; text on cassette reads, "Children, cluster house, play, Oglala authority, Pine Ridge"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 47)
    - Wounded Knee, 04/04/1993; singer_p_0466; text on cassette reads, "at home interview with FA son, location, Tom's band gordon, Nebraska"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 48)
    - Wounded Knee, 04/06/1993; singer_p_0467; text on cassette reads, "classes, interview with Shirley Garnette"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 48)
    - Wounded Knee, 04/06/1993; singer_p_0468; text on cassette reads, "School board, gray eagle elder, interview with Pine Ridge health administrator"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 48)
    - Wounded Knee, 04/07/1993; singer_p_0469; text on cassette reads, "Record 'Kili' from radio, bear butte, 'Charlotte' interview [sis of Tom], interview with John Steele, location, Wounded Knee, Kili Lakota woman, abuse Mother Earth"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 48)
    - Wounded Knee, 04/07/1993; singer_p_0470; text on cassette reads, "Landscape visuals Saturday drive, tape 1"; Hi8; running time 120:00 (Box 48)
- Teaching files
  - Cultural therapy, undated (Box 19)
  - Lectures
    - Diet, 1981 (Box 19)
    - Healing, 1977 (Box 19)
    - Occult, 1978-1991 (Box 19)
  - Lectures research
    - Holistic medical reprints, 1977-1980 (Box 20)
    - Some subcultural considerations in the psychotherapy of a negro patient, 1962 (Box 20)
    - Violence, Reflections on, 1969 (Box 20)
- Writings (Box 20)
  - "The abuse of healing or the failures of therapy", undated; handwritten notes (Box 20)
  - "Alternative Therapies and Allopathic Medicine -- Integration in the Year 2000?", 1993; conference speech draft (Box 20)
  - "American Institutions and Emerging Areas", circa 1960 (Box 24)
  - "Anthropological Films/Videos: Promise Not Yet Fulfilled," Choice, Jan 1992 (Box 20)
  - "Anthropology and Rectitude: Due Process as Obfuscation in the Enforcement of Professional Ethics", 1971; with Carl Vann (Box 20)
  - "The Australian Subincision Ceremony Reconsidered: Vaginal Envy or Kangaroo Bifid Penis Envy," American Anthropologist, 1967; with Daniel E. Desole (Box 20)
  - "Balanced Life Systems: A Test Tube for Life Science Research", 1965; a draft of a speech that was presented at the American Psychological Association meeting (Box 20)
  - Book introduction, An Essay on West African Therapeutics, Obahiah Johnson, 1982 (Box 20)
  - Book review, "The Endangered Sex: Neglect of Female Children in Rural North India," Barbara Miller, Journal of Psychoanalytic Anthropology, 1983 (Box 20)
  - "Carnage on the Roads", undated (Box 20)
  - "The Castaneda Trilogy as Literature and Anthropology", 1973 (Box 20)
  - "Caste and Identity in Guyana," Caste in Overseas Indian Communities, 1967 (Box 20)
  - "Children of the Dream Betray Spiritual Zionism", undated (Box 24)
  - "Collegians behind the Curtain: Two American students go to Hungary and Meet Marx out of the Textbook", 1948 (Box 20)
  - "Community Psychiatry and Community Development - The Psychiatrist as County Farm Agent", 1966 (Box 20)
  - "The Concept and Use of Pluralism in Anthropology," Michigan Conference of Political Scientists, 1970 (Box 20)
  - Consultation on traditional medicine, 1976; draft report (Box 20)
  - "Cultural Anthropology of Community Psychiatry," Medical Opinion and Review, Aug 1968; with Daniel E. Desole (Box 20)
  - "The Cultural Context of Latrogenic Complications," Incontri, Dec 1986 (Box 20)
  - "The Cultural of Poverty", 1965 (Box 20)
  - D.N. Pritt, circa 1947 (Box 20)
  - "Doctor's Medicine and Traditional Medicine - Same Issues for Dialogue," International Health News, Apr 1983; with Moon Jae Pak (Box 20)
  - "The Ethnography of the Paranormal," Phoenix: New Directions in the Study of Man v. 4 nos. 1 and 2, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Ex-Hitler Jugend Study on American Campuses (Part of American Program of Reeducation), 1950 (Box 20)
  - Extended comments on consultation on traditional medicine, 1976 (Box 20)